Finding Aid for the Mark Weber Jazz Collection, 1970-2005
UCLA Library Special Collections
Mark Weber Jazz Collection,
1970-2005
250
Weber, Mark
14 linear feet: 36 document boxes 211 digital images
University of California, Los Angeles. Library. Performing Arts Special Collections Los Angeles, California 90095-1575
The collection consists of photographs taken by Mark Weber relating to the experimental jazz musicians during the 1970's - 1990's, predominant focus on photos taken in Los Angeles from 1976-1985. Also included are notes, clippings, interview transcripts, correspondence, programs, flyers and articles.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF. Advance notice is required for access to the collection. Please contact UCLA Library Special Collections for paging information.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mark Weber; 2005.
Biography
"It would be a major disservice to a great art form to contain it within a defined orthodoxy. Without a definition it radiates outward. Nor would I care to venture a speculation as to what jazz is. I'm not too locked in on the word "jazz" anyway. If a cat (or kitty) can play, then he can play. Jazz is not a type of music, it is not a specific form or catagory. Jazz is a manner in which music is played. Jazz is the way you play the music, not the music that is played. Jazz is the original Free Form. It continues to evolve." -- Mark Weber.
Weber was born October 21, 1953 in Covina, Californa. His family came to California from Kansas in 1940 as part of the Great Depression/ Dustbowl migration and settled in Pomona. His interest in music began early on as he played country and folk guitar with his step-grandfather, Harry Matthew, for family functions. Weber grew up in the suburbs of Los Angeles and graduated from Upland High School in 1972. The jazz influence came about through listening to records and the radio. By the time he graduated, he was a "confirmed jazz & blues & avant garde musics devotee." In high school, Weber credits photography and his photography teacher, Jefferey Cole, with getting him through high school. In the 1970's and 80's, Mark Weber was witness to the experimental jazz scene in Los Angeles and recorded musicians and venues through photography as both devotee and friend.
Writing has been the focus of Weber's artistic direction. His first major literary work was a seven page letter "concerning the state of the house" to his mother. Weber wrote for his high school newspaper in 1971, but it wasn't until after his involvement with the Los Angeles jazz scene that he became caught up in chapbooks. He and poet/musician Gerald Locklin have published a number of well-received chapbooks.Weber's poetry has become the focal point of his life, although he sees no disconnect between music and poetry believing a good poet must be influenced by music. "So, let's just say that by and large, I'm scared to know what music poets listen to, in terms of music. It's not really their fault, they've been brainwashed by the industry. It's rare to find people who actually pay close enough attention to music to be knowing about it.You can hear it in their poems. Clunky. No flow. no ideas or development of ideas. All the poets who are influenced by Bukowski went to the liquor store, but did they listen to Mahler? Or Borodin? Bukowski was a romantic. You never heard him digging Bach/Baroque music and you never heard him speak of 20th century music -- it would have been great if he got some Ives, Cowell, Schoenberg, Webern, Berg, Bartok into his ears -- whew, he would have soared even more. Gerald Locklin can play the piano! He's a piano playing [expletive]. And it shows in his writings. And it shows in what he listens to. Ron Androla plays congas and listens far and wide. Fred Voss digs the blues. Todd Moore digs Mozart. These guys write their butts off. I've just always had high expectations for poets -- that they were a little more musically hip. But it hasn't always been my experience." -- Mark Weber
Weber has written poems, short stories, book reviews and for several music magazines. In June of 1976, his first monthly column in the international jazz music magazine, CODA, was published. He continued to write for CODA until 1990. Weber has since moved to New Mexico with his wife Janet Simon and publishes chapbooks by ZerxPress, a publishing house he started in Upland in 1983. In 1995, ZerxPress began publishing CDs as well. These days, Mark Weber paints and rennovates houses in New Mexico, publishes and DJ's a jazz show on KUNM every Thursday afternoon.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of photographs taken by Mark Weber relating to the experimental jazz musicians during the 1970's - 1990's, predominant focus on photos taken in Los Angeles from 1976-1985. Also includes notes, clippings, interview transcripts, correspondence, programs, flyers and articles.
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1. Mark Weber's description of Photographs, 1975-1976
Series 2. Mark Weber's research files
Series 3. Photographs
Series 4. Research files
Series 5. Mark Weber's other endeavors
Series 6. Related Material
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Weber, Mark--Archives; Jazz musicians--California--Los Angeles
Container List
- Photographs, Series 3.
  - Digital Objects, Subseries 1.; 211 digitized photographs
    The matted photographic prints scanned to create the digital objects are found in boxes 25-34.
    Digitized images of photographs in the collection, mostly taken from matted photographic prints and some color snapshots. Records under this heading will be moved to the appropriate subseries under Series 3 when multiple fields for digital objects are added. Digital objects not listed here remain on the UCLA Digital Library server until more digital object fields are added to individual records.
    - Akiyoshi, Toshiko, 1977 August 4; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 32)
    - Bill Berry Big Band, 1979 August 29 (Box 7)
    - Bill Evans Trio, 1977 May 5 (Box 7)
    - Bill Evans Trio, 1977 May 5; B&W 8x10 (Box 7)
    - Bill Evans Trio, 1977 May 5 (Box 7)
    - Blasters, 1981 September 11; B&W 8x10 (Box 8, Folder 6A)
    - Blevins, Bobby, 1976 November 11; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 32)
    - Bowie, Lester, 1979 October 20; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 32)
    - Bowie, Lester, 1979 October 20; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 32)
    - Bradford, Bobby, B&W 8x10 (Box 5)
    - Bradford, Bobby, 1976 September 5 (Box 5)
    - Bradford, Bobby, 1976 October 28 (Box 5)
    - Bradford, Bobby, 1976 October 28; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 32)
    - Bradford, Bobby, 1976 October 28; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 32)
    - Bradford, Bobby, 1976 October 3; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 32)
    - Bradford, Bobby, 1976 September 19; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 32)
    - Bradford, Bobby, 1976 September 12; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 32)
    - Bradford, Bobby, 1976 November 28; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 32)
    - Bradford, Bobby, 1977 April 24; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 32)
    - Bradford, Bobby, 1977 April 24; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 32)
    - Bradford, Booby, 1976 October 28 (Box 5)
    - Braxton, Anthony, 1979 October 20; B&W 8x10 (Box 31)
    - Brown, Ray, 8 x 10 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Burnett, Carl, 1979 January; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 31)
    - Burrell, Kenny, 1981 May 9 (Box 7)
    - Cables, George, 1979 February 17; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 31)
    - Callendar, Red, 1979 July 7; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 31)
    - Capp, Frank, 1979 May 27; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 31)
    - Capp, Frank, 1979 May 27; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 31)
    - Carter, Betty, 1976 December 4 (Box 7)
    - Carter, Betty, 1976 December 4; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 31)
    - Carter, John, 1976 August 31; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 31)
    - Carter, John, 1976 August 31; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 31)
    - Carter, John, 1978 January 3; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 31)
    - Chadbourne, Eugene, 1977 November 28; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 30)
    - Chenier, Clifton, 1977 November 5 (Box 7)
    - Cline, Alex, 1970s (Box 7)
    - Cobb, Jimmy, 1979 February; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 30)
    - Collins, Albert, 1977 August 14; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 30)
    - Collins, Albert, 1977 August 14; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 30)
    - Cray, Robert, 1977 August 14; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 30)
    - Cray, Robert, 1977 August 14; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 30)
    - Crayton, PeeWee, 1977 April 2; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 30)
    - Crayton, PeeWee, 1977 April 2; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 30)
    - Crouch, Stanley, 1979 October 20; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 30)
    - Farmer, Art, 1977 May 5 (Box 7)
    - Farris, Reverend Lonnie, 1979; 8 x 10 color (Box 9, Folder 8A)
    - Farris, Reverend Lonnie, 1977 October 28; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 30)
    - Favors, Malachi, 1979 October 20; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 30)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence, 1979 August 16; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 30)
    - Ferris, Glenn, 1979 April 14; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 30)
    - Ferris, Glenn, 1979 April 14; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 30)
    - Findley, Chuck, 1979 March 16; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 27)
    - Frishberg, Dave, 1979 May 23; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 30)
    - Frishberg, Dave, 1979 May 23; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 30)
    - Fulson, Lowell, 1978 August 12; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 30)
    - Ginsberg, Allen, 1977 January 25 (Box 29)
    - Gladden, Eddie, 1979 February 17; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 29)
    - Gladden, Eddie, 1979 February 17; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 29)
    - Golia, Vinny, 1979 October 28; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 29)
    - Golia, Vinny, 1979 October 28; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 29)
    - Gruntfest, John, 1978 August 19; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 29)
    - Guralnick, Tom, 1977 April 8; color snap (Box 6)
    - Guralnick,Tom, 1997 April 8; color snap (Box 6)
    - Haden, Charlie, 1981 January 26 (Box 8, Folder 2A)
    - Hemphill, Julius, 1977 September 11; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 29)
    - Hemphill, Julius, 1977 September 11; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 29)
    - Holloway, Red, 1977 July 18; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 29)
    - Hooker, John Lee, 1976 July 8; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 29)
    - Ida, Queen, 1978 August; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 28)
    - Ii, David, 1977 August 14; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 28)
    - Jackson, Milt, 1979 May 3; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 28)
    - Jackson, Milt, 1979 May 3; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 28)
    - Jarman, Joseph, 1979 October 20; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 28)
    - Jarman, Joseph, 1979 October 20; B&W 8x10 (Box 28)
    - Jordan, Lewis, 1978 August; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 28)
    - Jordan, Lewis, 1978 August; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 28)
    - Katz, Fred, 1979 March 20; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 28)
    - Katz, Fred, 1979 April 19; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 28)
    - Katz, Fred, 1979 April 19; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 28)
    - Katz, Fred, 1979 April 19; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 28)
    - Katz, Fred, 1979 April 19; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 28)
    - Kuntz, Henry Jr., 1977 September 29; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 28)
    - Kuntz, Henry Jr., 1978 December 19; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 28)
    - Lake, Oliver, 1977 December 18; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 27)
    - Lake, Oliver, 1978 January 3; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 27)
    - Lake, Oliver, 1978 January 3; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 27)
    - Land, Harold, 1977 July 10; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 27)
    - Land, Harold, 1977 July 10; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 27)
    - Land, Harold, 1977 July 10; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 27)
    - Levy, Lou, 1979 March 16; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 27)
    - Levy, Lou, 1979 March 16; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 27)
    - Lowe, Frank, 1976 July 2; B&W negative print 8x10, mounted (Box 27)
    - Lowe, Frank, 1976 July 2; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 27)
      see also negative print of this image at uclamus_250_00179
    - Lowe, Frank, 1976 July 2; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 27)
    - Marsh, Warne, 1977 January 26; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 27)
    - Marsh, Warne, 1977 February 6; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 27)
    - Menza, Don, 1979 March 16; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 27)
    - Menza, Don, 1979 March 16; B&W 8x10 (Box 27)
    - Miranda, Roberto, 1980 April 29 (Box 10, Folder 3A)
    - Mitchell, Blue, 1977 July 10; B&W 8x10 (Box 26)
    - Mitchell, Rosco, 1976 June 22; B&W 8x10 (Box 26)
    - Moore, Willie, 1978 August 12; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 26)
    - Murphy, Turk, 1979 August 15; B&W 8x10 (Box 26)
    - Murphy, Turk, 1979 April 15; B&W 8x10 (Box 26)
    - Murray, David, 1977 January 6; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 26)
    - Otis, Johnny, 1985 September 29 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Parker, Evan, 1978 October 29; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 26)
    - Pepper, Art (Box 10, Folder 10A)
    - Pepper, Art, 1982 January 15 (Box 20)
    - Pepper, Art, 1977 January 26 (Box 20)
    - Pepper, Art, 1977 April 27 (Box 20)
    - Pepper, Art, 1976 December 2; B&W 8x10 (Box 26)
    - Pepper, Art, 1977 January 26; B&W 8x10 (Box 26)
    - Pepper, Art, 1979 January; B&W 8x10 (Box 26)
    - Reid, Rufus, 1979 February 17; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 26)
    - Reid, Rufus, 1979 February 17; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 26)
    - Rhodes, Sonny, 1978 August 12; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 26)
    - Richardson, Jerome, 1999 June 10; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 26)
    - Roach, Max, 1977 January 8; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 26)
    - Rush, Otis, 1977 May 14; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 26)
    - Sams, George, 1978 August; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 25)
    - Silver, Horace, 1979 June 10; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 25)
    - Silver, Horace, 1979 June 10; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 25)
    - Tapscott, Horace (Box 5)
    - Tapscott, Horace, 1981 January 27 (Box 5)
    - Tapscott, Horace, 1977 January 30; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 25)
    - Tapscott, Horace, 1977 January 30; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 25)
    - Turner, Johnny, 1977 September 9; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 25)
    - Turner, Johnny, 1977 September 9; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 25)
    - Turner, Johnny, 1978 April 6; Color 8x10, mounted (Box 25)
    - Walker, Evans, 1977 February 2; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 25)
    - Walker, Evans, 1977 February 10; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 25)
    - Weber, Mark, 1983 June 7 (Box 5)
    - Wilber, Bob, 1979 May 23; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 25)
    - Wilber, Bob, 1979 May 23; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 25)
    - Wilson, Smokey, 1978; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 25)
      Also known as "Mississippi" Smokey Wilson
    - Wilson, Smokey, 1978 January 14; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 25)
    - Wilson, Smokey, 1978; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 25)
    - Wilson, Teddy, 1977 March 16; B&W 8x10, mounted (Box 25)
    - Wright, Lamar Jr., 1982 June 19 (Box 11, Folder 17A)
  - Color slides, Subseries 2.; Approx. 5,320 slides
    Boxes 16-21.
    Slides of artists represented in Series 3: Subseries 3 and 4, as well as artists represented exclusively in this subseries.
    - 1976,1978, 1980, 1993, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - 1977-1979 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - 1978, 1979, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - 1977-1980 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - 1977-1980 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - 1977-1980 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - 1977, 1978, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - 1982-1993 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - 1985, 1992, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - 1995-1997, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - 1995-1997,2000-2001 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - 1995-1997, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - 1996-1997 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - 1996-1997, Dec. 2004 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - 1997, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - 1997-1998 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - 1998-1999 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - 1999-2000 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - 1995-2003 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Artists, Subseries 3.; 258 photographs
    Arranged alphabetically.
    Photographs of artists in single and group portraits from Weber's photograph files. See also Series 1, Series 2 and Series 3: Subseries 1.
    - Abercrombie, John, 1944-, 2001 February 26; Color Snapshots 4x6 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Taken at Outpost in Albuquerque, New Mexico.
    - Alexander, Dave, 1938-, 1978 August; B&W (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Also known as Omar Hakim Khayyam. Taken in San Francisco, CA.
    - Allen, Chris, 2000 August 25; Color Snapshots 4x6 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      Albuquerque, New Mexico.
    - Anderson, Cat (William Alonzo), 1916-1981, 1979 August 29; B&W 8x10 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Soloist with the Bill Berry Big Band, taken at the Bonaventure Hotel in Los Angeles, CA.
      3 photographs.
    - Anderson, Ray, 1998 April 24; Color Snapshot (Box 6, Folder 6)
      RG Wells also in photograph.
      See also Series 3: Subseries 4, Ray Anderson Pocket Brass.
    - Andrews, Ernie, 1927-, 1985 September 29; B&W snapshots (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Anthony, Michael, 1996-2001,2005; B&W and color snapshots 4x6 and 5x7 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      Taken in Albuquerque (at Outpost) and Corrales, New Mexico. Also pictured; Arlen Asher, Sid Fendley, Jim Fox, David Parlato, Bud Shank, and Mark Weber.
      See also Series 3: Subseries 3, Parlato, Weber.
    - Baars, Ab (Abraham B., 1955- ), 2004 October 25; B&W (Box 6, Folder 11)
      Also pictured, Toby Delius.
    - Baker, David, 1931, 1988; Color snapshots 3x5 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      Taken in Cleveland, Ohio.
    - Baker, Duck, 2004 March 28; Color Snapshots 4x6 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      Taken in Albuquerque, New Mexico.
      See also Series 3: Subseries 3, Rudd, Roswell.
    - Barlow, Carla Kay, 2000 July 19; Color Snapshots 4x6 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      See also Series 3: Subseries 4, Out of Context.
    - Barry, Billy, 1976 September 30; B&W 8x10 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Basie, Count, 1904-1984, 1978 February 17 and 1980 April 10; B&W 8x10 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      Basie Orchestra in Claremont, Ca.
      See also Box 6: Folder 17
    - Basie, Count, 1904-1984, 1978 February 17 and 1980 April 10; B&W 5x7 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      Nat Pierce also pictured.
      See also Box 6: Folder 16
    - Battiste, Harold, 1931-, 1983 June 18; B&W 5x7 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      Taken with Bradford Marsalis at the Playboy Jazz Festival, Hollywood Bowl, Ca.
    - Berne, Tim, 1954-, 2000 November 13; Color snapshots 3x5 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Bidlack, Bruce, Circa late 1970's; B&W 5x7 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      Recording engineer who has worked with Tim Berne, Alex and Nels Cline.
    - Bishop, Walter Jr., 1927-1998, Circa late 1970's; B&W 8x10 and 5x7 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      Taken at the Hollywood Bowl
    - Booker, Walter, 1933-, 1979 February 23; B&W 8x10, 5x7 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Bradford, Bobby, 1934-, 1962, 1976-1983, 2004; B&W and color 8x10, 5x7, and color snaps (Box 5, Folder 1-5)
      Taken at such venues as Atlantic Studios in NYC; KPFK radio interview in Los Angeles, Little Big Horn 34 N. Mentor in Pasadena; Pasadena City College, and the University of New Mexico. Also pictured; Andrew Allison, Martin Banks, Clovis Bordeaux, Benjamin Bradford, Kevin Brandon, John Breckow, Kim Calkins, Terry Cannon, John Carter, Jesse James Church III, Henry Franklin, Diana Galas, Jimmy Garrison, John or Don Goldsmith, Vinny Golia, Tom Guralnick, Charlie Haden, Chuck Manning, Roy McCurdy, Roberto Miranda, O.C. Charles Moffett, Jimmy or James Perry Roberton, and Paul Vengelesti.
      See also series 3: Subseries 3, Carter, Ferris, Guralnick, Haden, Miranda, Newton. Series 3: Subseries 4, The Bobby Bradford Extet, The Bobby Bradford Sextet.Series 3: Subseries 1, for digital objects
    - Brashear, Oscar, 1944-, 1984 June 16; Color snapshots 3x5 (Box 6, Folder 26)
      Taken at the Hollywood Bowl, Los Angeles, Ca.
    - Braxton, Anthony, 1945-, 2003 April 2; Color Snapshots 3x5 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      Taken in Albuerqurque, NM. Also pictured; Gustavo Aguilar's band - Misc. Debris, Alan Luchusza and Chris Jonas.
    - Brooks, Bobby, 1983 March 20; Color snapshots 3x5 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Brown, Charles, 1977 Sept. 2; B&W 5x7 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Brown, Everett Jr., 1980 April 25; B&W 8x10 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Brown, Ray, 1926-2002, undated; B & W 8 x 10 (Box 6, Folder 31)
      Taken at the Playboy Jazz festival
    - Brown, Ted, 1927-, 2004 May 28; B&W and Color snapshots 3x5 (Box 6, Folder 32)
      Taken in Los Angeles, Ca. Also pictured Billy Bauer,Don Heckman, Lee Konitz, Dave Mackay, Kirk Silsbee, and Scott Yanow.
      See also Konitz, Lee
    - Bryant, Clora, 1983 June 19; B&W 5x7 (Box 6, Folder 33)
      Taken at the Playboy Jazz Festival, Hollywood Bowl, Los Angeles, Ca. Also pictured Bill Cosby, Bill Henderson, and Buster Williams.
    - Bryant, David, 1980 April 29; B&W 8x10 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Burrell, Kenny, 1931-, 1979 June 10 and 1981 May 9; B&W 8x10 (Box 6, Folder 35)
      Also pictured, Andy Simpkins.
    - Cables, George, 1944-, 1979-2003 inclusive; B&W 5x7 and color snapshots 4x6 (Box 6, Folder 37)
      Taken in Albuquerque, NM. Also pictured Sonny Fortune, Frank Morgan, and Dr. Janet Simon (Mark Weber's wife).
    - Carn, Doug (aka Abdul Rahim Ibrahim), 1948-, 1977 May 22; B&W 5x7 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Carroll, Baikida E.J., 1977 September 11; B&W 5x7 (Box 6, Folder 40)
      Also pictured, Julius Hemphill.
      See also Hemphill, Julius.
    - Carter, Betty, 1930-1988, 1976 Dec. 3-4 and undated; B&W 8x10 and 5x7 (Box 6, Folder 41)
      1976 photographs taken at the Howard Rumsey's Lighthouse in Hermosa Beach, Ca. Also pictured; Clifford Barbaro, Dennis Erwin, and John Hicks. Undated photograph taken at the Hollywood Bowl, Los Angeles, ca.
    - Carter, John, 1929-1991, 1976 - 1979, inclusive; B&W 8x10 and blue 8x10 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Venues include; The Speakeasy in L.A.,The Little Big Horn in Pasadena,Upland and Spectrum Studios in Venice Beach, Ca. Also pictured; Bobby Bradford, Chris Carter, Stanley Carter, Bahir Faruq Hasan, Julius Hemphill, Roberto Miranda,and William Jeffrey.
      See also; Series 3: Subseries 3 - Bradford, Crouch, Golia, Hemphill, Lake, Newton and Series 3: Subseries 4 - John Carter Ensemble
    - Carter, John, 1929-1991, 1976-1977, inclusive; B&W 5x7 and snapshots (Box 7, Folder 2)
      Venues include; Upland. Also pictured; Bahir Faruq Hasan, Julius Hemphill and William Jeffery.
      See also; Series 3: Subseries 4, John Carter Ensemble
    - Carter, John, 1929-1991, 1976-1984, inclusive; Color snapshots 3x5 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Venues include; Hollywood Bowl, Local 47 in Los Angeles and Spectrum Studios in Venice beach, Ca. Also pictured; Stanley Carter, Richard Davis, Vinny Golia, Melba Joyce, James Newton, and Gerald Oshita.
      See also; Series 3: Subseries 4, John Carter Ensemble.
    - Cesarano, Tony, 2004 July; B&W snapshots (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Chadbourne, Eugene, 1951-, 1977 and 1988; B&W 11x14 and 5x7 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Taken in Los Angeles and New York City.
      See also Box 36 for 11x14 prints.
    - Chambers, Joe, 1942-, 1985 September 29; B&W snapshot (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Chamblee, Eddie, 1920-, 1987 March 7; Color Snapshots (Box 7, Folder 6)
      Taken in New York City. Also pictured Jon Gordon, Ernest Hayes, and Jimmy Lewis.
    - Chapman, Emmett, 1984 April 5 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      Taken at California State Polytechnic University, Pomona. Chapman is the inventor of "the Stick" and a technique consisting in the action of the two hands tapping Perpendicularly on the strings. He made the first "Electric Stick" bodiless design in 1970.
    - Cheng, Raymond, 1981 February 14; B&W 5x7 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      Taken in San Francisco, Ca.
    - Chenier, Cleveland, 1921-1991, 1977 November 5; B&W 8x10 and 5x7 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      Taken at Verbum Dei Auditorium, 11100 South Central Ave., L.A., Ca.
      See also Series 3: Subseries 3, Chenier, Clifton.
    - Chenier, Clifton, 1925-1987, 1977 November 5; B&W 8x10 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      See also Series 3: Subseries 3, Chenier,Cleveland.
    - Clark, Buddy, 1929-, 1996 August 12; Color Snapshots (Box 7, Folder 11)
      Buddy Clark (from Supersax) and Robbie Wilkerson.
    - Cleveland, Jimmy, 1926-, 1979-1981, inclusive; B&W 8x10 and 5x7 (Box 7, Folder 12)